Daniel Mário de Lima, 30

São Carlos, SP, Brazil

+55 16 98832 3661 https://limadm.tk/ danielmariodelima@gmail.com

Systems Analyst, M.Sc. degree in Computer Science by the Institute of Mathematical and Computer Sciences (ICMC) of the University of São Paulo at São Carlos, Brazil. Proficient programmer and fast learner, with experience in several areas: software engineering, databases, distributed systems, networking, embedded systems, data mining, information visualization and machine learning. 5+ years of experience in software development for industrial and scientific applications. Currently researching deep learning applications for healthcare systems.

Education

PhD student in Computer Science, ICMC-USP (2017 – present)

Concentration Areas: Databases, Visualization, Deep Learning.

M.Sc. in Computer Science, ICMC-USP (2011 – 2013)

Concentration Areas: Databases, Visualization, Graph Theory and Applications.

B.Tech. in Information Systems, IFPI (2006 – 2008)

Certifications

Certified Tester Foundation Level, ISTQB (2009)

Experience

3yr. Systems Analyst at São Carlos. (Aug. 2014 – Jul. 2017)

Technical Support, Consulting and Development with private contractors and startups in projects of:

- Database systems and linux servers, web applications (RESTful APIs + HTML/CSS/JS front-end), Android apps, distributed computing services, NoSQL databases;
- Circuit design, embedded systems and remote sensing, using microcontrollers and single board computers (Arduino, AVR, PIC and Raspberry Pi);
- Data mining (cleaning, filtering, transformation and features), computer vision (OCR, object detection, GUI automation) and machine learning (statistical models and neural networks).

Public Repositories and Project reviews: Bitbucket, Codementor, Github, Upwork.

6mo. Teaching Assistant at ICMC-USP, São Carlos. 6h/week. (Aug. 2012 – Dec. 2012)

Course: Database Practice I. M.Sc. curricular component.

2yr. Software Developer at Infoway, Teresina. 44h/week. (Apr. 2009 – Jan. 2011)

Further development of the Colméia system and its proprietary web MVC framework. Java, Struts and Hibernate. (http://coopanest-ce.colmeiabrasil.com.br/)

1yr. Trainee at Infoway, Teresina. 20h/week. (Apr. 2008 – Mar. 2009)

Design and development of a complete ERP system for a cooperative of anesthesiologists (named Colméia) and its proprietary web MVC framework. Java, Struts and Hibernate.

Skills

Popular methods and tools:

- Project Management, Security and Quality Assurance (Testing / Integration);
- C11, C++17, ES6, Java8, Python, Ruby, and their ecosystems;
- MySQL, Oracle and PostgreSQL databases;
- Django, Hibernate / Spring, Rails and MEAN stacks;
- Android SDK / NDK and Haxe mobile development;
- Maven, VirtualEnvs, LXC, Docker and other deployment approaches;

Specialized technologies:

- Hadoop and AWS Lambda distributed computing;
- Cassandra and S3 distributed storage;
- Tarantool distributed storage and application server;
- HTML5 / CSS3, SVG, WebGL and D3.js for rich UIs and visualizations;
- CL, LuaJIT, Matlab / Octave, OpenMP, Orange, R, SageMath and many others;
- Caffe, Neon, TensorFlow, Torch and other NN libraries.

Traits

Careful thinking, pragmatic development and objective communication; Friendly, open-minded, adaptable to changes, teamworker, perfectionist, achiever, resilient; Hobbies: DIY, science, drama, exotic cultures, hiking and cycling.